# **Andrew Baxter**

P&D Coordinator

Phone: 317-446-1938

Email: asbaxter1@gmail.com

Site: https://asbaxter.github.io/my-portfolio/
GitHub: https://github.com/asbaxter

### Profile:

Professional and detail-oriented P&D Coordinator with over four years of management experience, who is transitioning to a career in software development. I am currently attending Butler's executive education courses for full stack development and was also learning to develop software before that point. At my current company I have progressed rapidly through multiple departments, proving time and time again my abilities to learn quickly, adapt to change, and solve problems. I look forward to starting a career in software development and I am excited to see what skills and knowledge I can bring to a new industry.

# **Professional Experience:**

#### FedEx Ground / P&D Coordinator / May 2022 - Present

Responsible for coordinating the operations between FedEx Ground and their service providers. As a coordinator I must maintain good business relationships with service providers while also holding them accountable to contractual standards and performance agreements.

#### FedEx Ground / Sort Manager / Oct 2021 – May 2022

Responsible for maintaining the day-to-day operations of one of the most successful FedEx facilities in the world. Lead hundreds of employees by creating a culture of safety, efficiency and integrity. Responsible for the quality and timely delivery of tens of thousands of costumer packages daily.

## FedEx Ground / Area Manager / Jan 2021 – Oct 2021

- Developed and trained operations mangers to run efficient and well-organized areas, while maintaining company values and quality metrics
- Increased weekend sort efficiency by 10% by reengineering destinations to a more consolidated area, reducing sort times and total labor hours

## FedEx Ground / Operations Manager / Dec 2018 - Jan 2021

- Lead multiple teams of package handlers through different areas of the operation while always maintaining safety, efficiency, and integrity
- As a control room manager, I cut our controllable rehandle percentage in half using root cause analysis and trend tracking to better position and train facers (Jam Breakers)

#### We Do Windows / Field Supervisor / May 2018 - Feb 2020

Lead a team of window washers who gave hundreds of costumers a professional, high quality window washing experience.

#### **Education:**

## Butler Executive Education (May 2022 - Present)

Full Stack Developments

# Ball State University (2014 – 2018)

100 credit hours completed towards, major in criminal justice and a minor in digital forensics

# Skills:

HTML
CSS
Node.js
JavaScript
Bootstrap
Materialize